Adult Education Audio and Video Collection
Adult Education Audio and Video Collection
1952-1995
Syracuse University Publications in Continuing Education
21 linear ft.
Audio and video recordings of a variety of adult education events and topics, including interviews, colloquiums, presentations, lectures, speeches, broadcasts, and more.
2563018
Biographical History
The collection of audio and video recordings at Syracuse University began as a project of University College to record the voices of important figures in adult education. It grew to include recordings from the University of Georgia's Mentor I and II programs and Gretchen Bersch's "Conversation on Lifelong Learning" project, as well as Dr. Charters' own personal recollections and collection of tapes. SUPCE publications MSS 37 and 48, "Adult Education Sound and Video Recordings," published in 1992 and 2003, listed most of this material but have been superceded by this finding aid.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Adult education audio and video collection contains audio and video recordings of a variety of adult education events and topics, including interviews, colloquiums, presentations, lectures, speeches, broadcasts, and more. The collection is divided by format. Reel-to-reel recordings include among other things material from the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, the "Sing Your America" series from Encyclopedia Britannica, a set of 90+ interviews of adult educators collected by Herbert Hunsaker under the title "Extending the Resources of the University into the community," and "People Under Communism," a series of lectures on the Soviet Union and communism by Merle Fainsod, Alex Inkeles, and Harold Fisher, all of Harvard University. Audiocassettes consists of interviews, addresses, seminars, and more, including 17 interviews of adult educators done by Joseph W. Jacque. U-Matic videotapes contains tapes of two colloquia and a seminar held at Syracuse University in 1980 and 1981. Videocassettes contains recordings of Gretchen Bersch's Mentor I and Mentor II series, interviews with significant figures in the early evolution of adult education as a field. Interviewees include Paul Essert, Herbert Hunsaker, Wilbur Hallenbeck, Cyril Houle, Malcolm Knowles, Phyllis Cunningham, William Griffith, George Aker, Alexander Charters, and more.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is divided by media format and then in numerical order by tape number. Tapes within the boxes may have shifted during transport.
Related Material
has a number of collections related to adult education, both of individuals and organizations. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Separated Material
All of the tapes labeled with "VT" numbers are held by Syracuse University Archives.
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Adler, Mortimer Jerome, 1902-2001.; Bersch, Gretchen.; Blakely, Robert J.; Charters, Alexander N.; Essert, Paul L.; Hendrickson, Andrew, 1899-; Houle, Cyril O. (Cyril Orvin), 1913-1998.; Hunsaker, Herbert Cason, 1898-; Knowles, Malcolm S. (Malcolm Shepherd), 1913-1997.; McClusky, Howard Y., 1900-1982.; Mezirow, Jack, 1923-2014.; Sheats, Paul H., 1907-; Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions.; Junto 2000.; Mentors I (University of Georgia).; Mentors II (University of Georgia).; Conversations on lifelong learning (University of Alaska).; Adult education.; Adult education teachers -- Interviews.; Citizenship -- Education.; Comparative education.; Continuing education.; Distance education -- United States.; Educators -- United States -- Interviews.; Audiocassettes.; Videotapes.; Adult education teachers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to the tapes requires advance notice for production of a listening copy.
Acquisition Information
Various. Tapes 8900 through 8909, gift of Alex Charters, 2016.
Inventory
- Reel to reel tapes
  - 0352-01 The Quantitative Society. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0364-01 The Technological Order. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0365-01 Britain in the Common Market. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0366-01 Malstructure in the Common Market. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 1)
  - 0367-01 Capitalism and Democracy. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0368-01 Religion in the Schools. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0369-01 The Warless World. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 1)
  - 0370-01 The Will of Zeus. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0371-01 Educational Bankruptcy. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 1)
  - 0372-01 India and its Leaders:Two Interviews. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0373-01 The Eichmann Trial and the Rule of Law. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0374-01 The Political Animal. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (55:00) (Box 1)
  - 0375-01 On Revolution. Center for the Study of Demo­cratic Institutions. (58:00) (Box 1)
  - 0376-01 Zuckerkandl. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (55:00) (Box 1)
  - 0377-01 Hutchins on Israel and Europe. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (45:00) (Box 1)
  - 0378-01 Psychological Aspects of Nuclear War. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0379-01 Freedom from Myths. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0380-01 A Financier Views the Economic Scene. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0381-01 Two faces of Federalism. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0382-01 Is Wisdom Enough Today? Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0383-01 The Chosen People. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0384-01 South Africa's Racial Problems. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0385-01 A Vision of the End. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 1)
  - 0386-01 Pension Funds and the Economy. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0387-01 New Nations and World Order. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (75:00) (Box 1)
  - 0388-01 The Sources of Labor Power. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0389-01 Technology and the Public Good. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0390-01 The Vision of the Artist. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (40:00) (Box 1)
  - 0391-01 "Pacem in Terris": The Pope's Encyclical. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0392-01 Techno1ogy and the Fine Arts. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0393-01 German Catholics and Hitler's Wars. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 1)
  - 0394-01 The College: Expectations and Implications. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (45:00) (Box 1)
  - 0395-01 The Economic Paradox. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 1)
  - 0396-01 Alienation and Freedom. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 2)
  - 0397-01 Government by Governance. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 2)
  - 0398-01 A Visit to the Dominican Republic. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0399-01 Education:For What and For Whom? Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0400-01 Democracy, Planning, and Participation. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0401-01 Concentrations of Private Power. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0402-01 The Bill of Rights and the Economic Republic. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00), adulted_019 (Box 2)
  - 0403-01 The Responsibilities of Television. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0404-01 The Responsibilities of the Press. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0405-01 Government and Politics: Strengths and Weak­nesses. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00), adulted_020 (Box 2)
  - 0406-01 The Society of the Qualified Man. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0407-01 The Prospects for Democracy Around the World. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0408-01 The Citizen and Foreign Policy. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 2)
  - 0409-01 Communication in a Democracy. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 2)
  - 0410-01 America: Liberal or Conservative. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 2)
  - 0411-01 Questions About Democracy. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 2)
  - 0412-01 No Time for Heroes. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 2)
  - 0413-01 Buy Less And Enjoy It. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 2)
  - 0414-01 Civil Rights in Israel. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (40:00) (Box 2)
  - 0415-01 Who Will Blow the Trumpet? Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 2)
  - 0416-01 Black and White in America. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00), adulted_021 (Box 2)
  - 0417-01 A Wa1k on the West Side. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (45:00) (Box 2)
  - 0418-01 The Jury: Safeguard or Anachronism? Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (45:00) (Box 2)
  - 0419-01 Culture in Broadcasting: Do We Really Want It'? Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0420-01 Literary Illiterates. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (45:00) (Box 2)
  - 0421-010 My America! Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (15:00) (Box 2)
  - 0422-01 The Children of Chafetz Chaim. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0423-01 No Lamb for Slaughter. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0424-01 The Nurture of Human Life. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (45:00) (Box 2)
  - 0425-01 The First Amendment: The Schools and Religion. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 2)
  - 0426-01 States' Abilities, Not States' Rights. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0427-01 The Marble-Cake of Government. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0428-01 The Legislator's Eighteen-Hour Day. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 2)
  - 0429-01 Government and Politics: Strengths and Weaknesses. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 2)
  - 0430-01 An "Establishment" of Religion. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 2)
  - 0431-01/02 First Things First. Part I and II. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (70:00) (Box 3)
  - 0432-01 New Utopias: Looking Backward or Brave New World? Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 3)
  - 0433-01 A Socialist Knight at the Center. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 3)
  - 0434-01 The Anti-Poverty War. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 3)
  - 0435-01 Is There a New South? Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 3)
  - 0436-01 Can There Be a Dialogue Between Christians and Marxists? Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 3)
  - 0437-01 Peace Requires Peacemakers. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 3)
  - 0438-01/03 A View From Rome. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions.
    - 0438-01 I. The Vatican Council. (50:00) (Box 3)
    - 0438-02 II. The Vatican Council. (60:00) (Box 3)
    - 0438-03 III. The Decline of Romania. (45:00) (Box 3)
  - 0439-01/03 A View of the Economy. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions.
    - 0439-01 I. From a Free-Marketer. (60:00) (Box 3)
    - 0439-02 II. From a Democratic Socialist. (60:00) (Box 3)
    - 0439-03 III. From a Marxist. (60:00) (Box 3)
  - 0440-01 A Look at the Yugoslavian Economy. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 3)
  - 0441-01 Science: For Truth or Good? Part I with Helmut Krauch and Part II with Linus Pauling. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 3)
  - 0442-01 Forty Million Words. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 3)
  - 0443-01 Beyond the Smoke-Filled Rooms. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 3)
  - 0444-01 The Kibbutz Revisited. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 3)
  - 0445-01 A Visit with the Pau1ings. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (45:00) (Box 3)
  - 0446-01/02 Freedom of the Press. Part I and II. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (120:00) (Box 3)
  - 0447-01 Reapportioning the States. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 3)
  - 0448-01 The Supreme Court as History. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 3)
  - 0449-01 Has the Court Usurped the Powers of Congress? Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 3)
  - 0450-01 The Ethics of Compensatory Justice. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (45:00) (Box 3)
  - 0451-01 Beauty for Ashes. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (30:00) (Box 3)
  - 0452-01 Winds of Change. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60:00) (Box 3)
  - 0453-01 Gains in Mississippi. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (15:00) (Box 3)
  - 0454-01 Our Technological Society. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (60.00) (Box 3)
  - 0455-01 "To Turn the Other Cheek." Dr. Ole Holsti, Professor of Political Science at The University of British Columbia, Vancouver. Broadcasting Foundation of America. (23:20) (Box 3)
  - 0456-01 "To Turn the Other Cheek." Dr. Lionel Elvin, Director, The Institute of Education, University of London. Broadcasting Foundation of America. (24:00) (Box 4)
  - 0457-01 "The Virus of Violence." Alex Haley. Syracuse University. (Box 4)
  - 0458-01/05 Sing Your America Series. Encyclopedia Britannica Films Recording.
    - 0458-01 An Old Heritage and a New Country. Early Colonial Songs. (Box 4)
    - 0458-02 New Songs for a New Country. Songs of the Revolution and Westward Ex­pansion. (Box 4)
    - 0458-03 Songs of the Frontier and Western Trails. (Box 4)
    - 0458-04 Americans All. Music of Our Many Heritages. (Box 4)
    - 0458-05 Lanes to the World. Songs of the Sailors. (Box 4)
  - 0459-01 That a College Education Does not Equip a Woman for Her Role in a Modern World. Colorado Tapes for Teaching. (29:40) (Box 4)
  - 0460-01 Education of the Negro. Colorado Tapes for Teaching. (30:00), adulted_022 (Box 4)
  - 0461-01 Civil Defense. (Prepare for Survival Series) Colorado Tapes for Teaching. (30:00) (Box 4)
  - 0462-01 Civil Defense Today. (Prepare for Survival Series) Colorado Tapes for Teaching. (30:00) (Box 4)
  - 0463-01/10 Community Leadership Institute. Estes Park, 1st., July 16-20, 1956 (Box 4)
  - 0464-01/09 Community Leadership Institute. Estes Park, 2nd., June 30-July 6, 1957 (Box 4)
  - 0465-01/10 Community Leadership Institute - Bigwin., June 28-Ju1y 10, 1953 (Box 5)
  - 0466-01/10 Community Leadership Institute - Bigwin., July 12-Ju1y 19, 1954 (Box 5)
  - 0467-01 A View from Eucalyptus Hill. Hutchings, Robert. Discussion with U.N. Delegates. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions., May 1963 (Box 5)
  - 0468-01 Trade union leaders of the United Auto Workers discuss their problems with Paul Jacobs and W. H. Ferry at the Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions. (Box 5)
  - 0469-01 Dennis Heally, Member of the British Parliament and a Member of the Shadow Cabinet for the Labor Party in Charge of Commonwealth Affairs, discusses Britain and the Common Market. Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions., May 1962 (Box 5)
  - 0470-01/04 Jazz in Transition
    - 0470-01/02 Types of jazz outlined: New Orleans, Swing, Bop, and Progressive. (Box 5)
    - 0470-03/04 Styles of jazz outlined. (Box 5)
  - 0471-01/97 Extending the Resources of the University into the community. Personal Interviews collected by Herbert C. Hunsaker, Purdue University., 1953-1954 (Box 5)
    - 0471-01 Roy R. Tompkins; W. S. Bittner. (Box 5)
    - 0471-02 W. S. Bittner; Harold Van Cleave; Donald Searcy. (Box 5)
    - 0471-03 Van Cleave and Searcy, concl.; Paul H. Sheats. (Box 5)
    - 0471-04 Paul H. Sheats, conc1.; L. H. Adolphson. (Box 5)
    - 0471-05 George E. Dotson. (Box 5)
    - 0471-06 Robert Haas. (Box 5)
    - 0471-07 Bethel Fite; E. S. Charmichael; Graydon Ausmus. (Box 5)
    - 0471-08 Graydon Ausmus, concl.; Henry B. Moore. (Box 5)
    - 0471-09 J. G. Sullivan; J. P. Cosand. (Box 5)
    - 0471-10 Hiram W. Edwards; Grace Bird. (Box 5)
    - 0471-11 Thomas C. Holy; A. C. Rowbotham; George C. Halverson. (Box 5)
    - 0471-12 Baldwin Woods; Jack London (Box 5)
    - 0471-13 Maurice Donohue; H. Talmadge. (Box 5)
    - 0471-14 David Ackley; Eugene Johnson. (Box 5)
    - 0471-15 Raymond Allen. (Box 5)
    - 0471-16 [unknown] (Box 5)
    - 0471-17 B. Lamar Johnson. (Box 5)
    - 0471-18 Irving Webber; Chief of Police Jornar (Gainsville, Fla.) (Box 5)
    - 0471-19 A. B. Martin; George Mitchell. (Box 5)
    - 0471-20 Barnett Williams; Report of interview with Dean Biscoe of the University of Georgia. (Box 5)
    - 0471-21 Henry Becker; E. R. Harty; Vernon Fox; William Leap. (Box 5)
    - 0471-22 W. T. Arnett; Faculty Seminar on Community Planning, U. of Florida. (Box 5)
    - 0471-23 Faculty Seminar on Community Planning, U. of Florida, concl.; T. L. Smith. (Box 5)
    - 0471-24 George B. Zehmer. (Box 5)
    - 0471-25 Mr. and Mrs. Jess S. Ogden. (Box 5)
    - 0471-26 Henry Clark, M.C.; R. P. Wolff. (Box 5)
    - 0471-27 Omar C. Aderhoid. (Box 5)
    - 0471-28 Howard Odum. (Box 6)
    - 0471-29 Ernest A. Lowe. (Box 6)
    - 0471-30 W. A. Sutton; W. A. King; T. L. Walton. (Box 6)
    - 0471-31 Mr. and Mrs. William W. Biddle. (Box 6)
    - 0471-32 William W. Biddle, concl.; Herbert Thelan. (Box 6)
    - 0471-33 Herbert Thelan, concl.; Phillip Hauser. (Box 6)
    - 0471-34 Maurice Donohue. (Box 6)
    - 0471-35 L. R. Siebert. (Box 6)
    - 0471-36 Richard Poston. (Box 6)
    - 0471-37 Frederick Killian; R. A. Nunnemacher. (Box 6)
    - 0471-38 Jefferson, President of Clark University. (Box 6)
    - 0471-39 Donald Stone. (Box 6)
    - 0471-40 S. M. Menton; C. A. Bosworth. (Box 6)
    - 0471-41 Edward Harden. (Box 6)
    - 0471-42 Harry Towsley, M.D. (Box 6)
    - 0471-43 L. McKune; G. R. Garrison. (Box 6)
    - 0471-44 Paul A. Miller. (Box 6)
    - 0471-45 w. Dickerman; Everett J. Soop. (Box 6)
    - 0471-46 Rensis Likert. (Box 6)
    - 0471-47 Lorenz Straub; J. L. Miller. (Box 6)
    - 0471-48 J. L. Miller, concl.; T. J. Shannon; J. R. Donoghue. (Box 6)
    - 0471-49 Robert A. Polson. (Box 6)
    - 0471-50 Donald Van Cleave. (Box 6)
    - 0471-51 G. L. Simpson; G. W. Blackwell. (Box 6)
    - 0471-52 Albert Coats; Rex Winslow. (Box 6)
    - 0471-53 T. Hale Ham; John Maddox. (Box 6)
    - 0471-54 J. T. Wearn; John Maddox. (Box 6)
    - 0471-55 Mrs. Mabel Mack. (Box 6)
    - 0471-56 W. C. Jones; Viron Moore. (Box 6)
    - 0471-57 Portland State Extension Center Building Planning Commission, Frairchers, Hummel, Harris, Parker, and Spalding. (Box 6)
    - 0471-58 Portland State Extension Center Building Planning Commission, concl.; J. C. Caughlan. (Box 6)
    - 0471-59 Charles McKinley; M. L. Goldschmidt; E. W. Wengert. (Box 6)
    - 0471-60 Roben Maaske; W. C. Ballaine. (Box 6)
    - 0471-61 Paul S. Beaver. (Box 6)
    - 0471-62 E. L. Keller; W. P. Dickinson; H. R. Albrecht. (Box 6)
    - 0471-63 Fred Hoehler; Ron Donovan; K. L. Holderman. (Box 6)
    - 0471-64 s. H. Campbell; O. R. MacKenzie. (Box 6)
    - 0471-65 M. S. Eisenhower; M. R. Trabue. (Box 6)
    - 0471-66 Paul A. Wessler; Ross Walsh. (Box 7)
    - 0471-67 Ross Walsh, concl.; W. C. Graham; H. S. Zimmerman. (Box 7)
    - 0471-68 H. S. Zimmerman; Mrs. Wayne Stevens; Mrs. Peter Larson. (Box 7)
    - 0471-69 Urban University Conference. Castle Rock, Washington. (Box 7)
    - 0471-70 Donald H. Webster; Nathanael Engle; Jack Wright. (Box 7)
    - 0471-71 Jack Wright, concl. (Box 7)
    - 0471-72/79 University of California Extension Division Workshop on Community Development., 8 tapes (Box 7)
    - 0471-80 Stanley Taylor; Mrs. Fred Radke. (Box 7)
    - 0471-81 Mrs. Fred Radke, concl.; James Frits. (Box 7)
    - 0471-82 Keith McCoy; Eugene Hayes. (Box 7)
    - 0471-83 Eugene Hayes, concl.; T. F. Paulsen. (Box 7)
    - 0471-84 T. F. Paulsen, concl; Paul Webb. (Box 7)
    - 0471-85 Paul Webb, concl.; Mrs. Leon Hilts. (Box 7)
    - 0471-86 Urban University - Final Session Discussion. (Box 7)
    - 0471-87 Paul Sheats - Seminar with Richard Poston. (Box 7)
    - 0471-88 Paul Sheats - Seminar with Richard Poston, concl.; Eugene Johnson. (Box 7)
    - 0471-89 R. E. Gard; W. B. Thiede. (Box 7)
    - 0471-90 W. B. Thiede, concl.; L. Sorden. (Box 7)
    - 0471-91 R. J. Colbert. (Box 7)
    - 0471-92 W. A. Wittich. (Box 7)
    - 0471-93 Abbott Kaplan. (Box 7)
    - 0471-94 Edward W. Davis; C. C. Ludwig. (Box 7)
    - 0471-95 C. C. Ludwig, concl.; H. G. Heneman; Theodore Caplow. (Box 7)
    - 0471-96 John Ivey, Jr.; Southern Regional Education Board - Atlanta, Georgia. (Box 7)
    - 0471-97 Hollis Rinehart; J. B. Culpepper. (Box 7)
  - 0472-01/04 AMVETS Seminar in Public Responsibility. Georgetown University, October 25-30, 1959 (Box 7)
  - 0472-05/23 AMVETS Seminar in Public Responsibility (cont.). Georgetown University, October 25-30, 1959 (Box 8)
  - 0473-01/21 People Under Communism. National Association of Educational Broadcasters. (Box 8)
    - 0473-01 Terror as a System of Power. (Box 8)
    - 0473-02 Music to Order. (Box 8)
    - 0473-03 The Men Who Make the Migs. (Box 8)
    - 0473-04 Drama to Order. (Box 8)
    - 0473-05 Literature to Order. (Box 8)
    - 0473-06 Pattern of World Conflict. (Box 8)
    - 0473-07 Music and the Dream. (Box 8)
    - 0473-08 "The Russian Revolutionary Movement and the Rise of Bolshevism" by Professor Merle Fainsod of Harvard. (Box 8)
    - 0473-09 "The Loyalty of the Soviet People" by Professor Merle Fainsod of Harvard. (Box 8)
    - 0473-10 "The Aims, Strengths, and Weaknesses of Soviet Strategy" by Professor Merle Fainsod of Harvard. (Box 8)
    - 0473-01/21 People Under Communism. National Associa­tion of Educational Broadcasters. (Box 8)
    - 0473-11 "The Soviet Attack on the Voice of America" by Professor Merle Fainsod of Harvard. (Box 8)
    - 0473-12 "Letters to the Editor: Soviet Style" by Dr. Alex Inkeles of Harvard. (Box 8)
    - 0473-13 "The Soviet Literary Straightjacket" by Professor Ernest J. Simmons of Columbia. (Box 8)
    - 0473-14 "Communist Front Organizations and Communist Prisoners of War" by Professor Harold H. Fisher of Stanford. (Box 8)
    - 0473-15 "Communism in Japan" by Professor Harold H. Fisher of Stanford. (Box 8)
    - 0473-16 ‘Communism in China" by Professor Harold H. Fisher of Stanford. (Box 8)
    - 0473-17 ‘Communism in India" by Professor Harold H. Fisher of Stanford. (Box 8)